In this segment I'm going to talk about Jack completing his backswing.
Know thy self, and Jack knew himself.
And he knew when his game was off, his first check point was, am I completing my backswing?
And by completing a backswing to him that meant extension, full arm swing, full shoulder turn, and full wrist hinge.
Completing the backswing.
When he didn't complete his backswing, very often like many of us, if you don't complete your backswing you make a move, you're in front of the ball, club face is open moving to the right, push fade.
And that's what Jack would do most of the time if he didn't complete his backswing.
But the point is he knew the major mistake in his swing, he knew the first thing that went wrong.
Do you know the first thing that goes wrong when you start hitting the ball poorly?
Even if your answer is yes, you may not be correct.
And how many of you discard that swing and bring in another swing, a relief pitcher, oh I'll try that, I'll try that.
Jack knew. If he started hitting poorly, the first place he looked, did he complete his backswing? Full arm swing, full shoulder turn, full wrist hinge.
And it also wouldn't hurt you, if you start hitting the ball poorly an excellent place to look first is, are you completing your backswing.
Because if you're not completing your backswing, the only thoughts that will help you, is a manipulative Band-Aid that in the future is going to hurt you, more than it's going to help you.
Be like Jack, you're starting to make some mistakes on the course, make sure you're completing your backswing.